Senior Software Engineer Yahor But-Husaim



SUMMARY

13+ years of hands-on experience in Software Development, Java, E-Commerce, Travel, Fintech domains, Spring, ATG/Endeca (Oracle Web Commerce), Agile methodologies (SAFe, Scrum, Kanban, XP).

Responsibilities: solution design and development, maintenance, performance optimization, code review and refactoring, mentoring, interviewing. Communication with client, planning, reporting, events and meetings facilitation.

Strengths: ability to self organize and focus on work, attentive to detail, responsible and reliable, optimistic, good communication skills, team player, work with focus on success.

LEADING STACK

Java 8-17, Oracle ATG/Endeca Web Commerce, Spring Framework, Boot, MVC, Data, Security, Integration, Cloud, Vaadin, Monolithic/Microservices, WebSocket, REST, OpenAPI, gRPC, JPA, Hibernate, JMS, AMQP, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Weblogic, WildFly, Tomcat, Jetty, Nginx, Apache, Oracle DB, MSSQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Coherence, MongoDB, Redis, Liquibase, Elasticsearch, Druid, Unit/integration testing, TDD, JUnit, Mockito, Selenium, JS, jQuery, Vue.js, node.js, Ant, Maven, Gradle, Git, Mercurial, SVN, Cl/CD, Jenkins, GitLab, Sonar, Docker, k8s, ELK, Grafana, AWS, Linux, Python, Groovy, UML, Image recognition algorithms, OpenCV.

MAIN ACTIVITIES

Lead / Senior Software Engineer; Team Lead/Project Coordinator/Scrum Master; Interviewer, Mentor.

LANGUAGES

English — **B2 Upper Intermediate**

French — A1 Elementary

EDUCATION

Computer science | 2012

Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Product	GP Solutions PropertyVIEW (travel)
Period	03/2023 - 12/2023
Role	Senior Software Engineer
Description	PropertyVIEW is AI-powered content monitoring and distribution management software offering the hospitality industry solutions to streamline and optimize content all in one place. Primary objective: Transit from crafting to assembly line model.
Responsibilities	 System redesign, Solution design and development;

- Discussing and implementation of architecture improvements;
- Discussing and implementation of new features, bug fixing, code reviewing & refactoring; performance optimization;
- Implementation of unit & E2E tests;
- CI/CD implementation;
- Mentoring, interviewing.

Achievements: successful system redesign and implementation of "crowdsourcing marketplace"-like model; gained expertise in image recognition algorithms, OpenCV and the travel domain.

Used Technologies

Java 11, Spring Boot, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Druid, OpenCV, Vaadin, REST, gRPC, Hibernate, SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Liquibase, ELK, Maven, Git, Mercurial, Jenkins, Docker Swarm, Groovy, Junit, Mockito, Selenium, UML, node.js, Vue.js

Product	Forte Group LETU (e-commerce)	
Period	10/2020 - 12/2022	

Role

Lead Software Engineer, SAFe Scrum Master

Description

L'Etoile (letu.ru) is the largest cosmetics and perfume retailer in Russia. Primary objective: transformation of monolithic platform (ATG) to microservices architecture using a domain-driven design approach;

Team: 250 people, 10 locations.

Responsibilities

- Solution design and development;
- Discussing and implementation of architecture improvements, creating POCs for decision making;

- Discussing and implementation of new features;
- CI/CD implementation;
- Mentoring, Interviewing;
- Facilitating team events and processes, supporting teams and ARTs in delivering value, coaching.

Achievements: successful on-the-fly transformation of ATG/Endeca platform, SAFe Scrum Master certification.

Used Technologies

Java 8, 17, Oracle ATG/Endeca Web Commerce, Spring Framework, Boot, MVC, Data, Security, Integration, Cloud, Monolithic/Microservices, REST, OpenAPI, gRPC, JPA, Hibernate, JMS, Kafka, WildFly, Nginx, SQL, MSSQL Server, PostgreSQL, Coherence, Redis, Liquibase, Elasticsearch, Unit/integration testing, TDD, JUnit, Mockito, Vue.js, node.js, Gradle, Git, CI/CD, Jenkins, GitLab, Sonar, Docker, k8s, ELK, Grafana, AWS, Linux, Python, UML.

Product	Decegram (fintech)
Period	08/2019 - 09/2020
Role	Team Lead
Description	Development of decentralized Telegram-based crypto platform combining P2P-exchange, trading, auctions, merchant service and wallets.
Responsibilities	 System design, decision making; Solution design and development; Team management, interviewing, mentoring; Consulting.

	Achievements: "zero to one" MVP of a P2P crypto exchange platform that offers more than 200 pairs of different digital assets; gained small start-up product experience and expertise in the fintech domain.
Used Technologies	Python3, Java 11, MTProto, TDLib, ccxt, Telethon, Spring Boot, WebSocket, REST, Postgres, Redis, Docker, Gradle, Git, Heroku
Project	EPAM NBTY-ATG (e-commerce)
Period	08/2014 - 07/2019
Role	Lead Software Engineer, Project Coordinator
Description	Retail & Distribution NBTY EU (Holland & Barrett brand) is the UK's leading retailer of vitamins, minerals and herbal supplements. https://www.hollandandbarrett.com/ (.ie, .nl, .be) https://www.gnc.co.uk/ NBTY Europe, a leading health food retailer that encompasses Holland & Barrett, Nature's Way (H&B IE), GNC, De Tuinen (H&B NL) and Essenza (H&B BE). NBTY is developing the retail and online commercial strategies, new store development, buying and marketing strategies and franchising of the Holland & Barrett brand worldwide. NBTY Europe has chosen Oracle Commerce Suite to create a platform to help optimize retail operations and support its developing online business in Europe. Team: 60 people (project peak), 3 locations, 5 years.
Responsibilities	 Development and customization, ATG/Endeca, Endeca Workbench, SEO, Sitemap, Search, Relevance Ranking, TypeAhead, Refinements, Multisite (H&B, GNC, NW, DT, BE), Merchandising; bug fixing, code reviewing, refactoring.

 Communication with customers, planning, reporting, events and meetings facilitation.

Achievements: Technical leadership and project coordination, Scrum mastering, reports automatization, spikes integration.

Redesigned checkout, product group categories (non catalog),
Merchandising workflow access control, Endeca Workbench content indexing, new brands (multisite), ATG/Endeca upgrade path investigation and how-to, Bazaarvoice, Rich Relevance, Adyen,
Ingenico, Paypal, AliPay payments integration, OrderGroove,
HealthBox, Data migration to Commerce Tools.

Used Technologies

Database: Oracle DB 11gR2.

Tools: Eclipse, Oracle Weblogic, SQL Developer, Fiddler, jRebel, Git, SVN, Ant, Amazon WorkSpaces, Jenkins, JUnit, Jira, Confluence. Technologies: ATG 10.1.1: Commerce, Endeca XM, Endeca Search, User profile, Data Anywhere Architecture, Content Administration; ATG 11, Java EE 6, Java EE 8, JSP, SQL, JavaScript, JQuery, jsViews, Groovy, Agile.

Project	EPAM NBTY-COMM (e-commerce)
Period	08/2013 - 08/2014
Role	Senior Software Engineer
Description	Retail & Distribution NBTY EU (Holland & Barrett brand) is the UK's leading retailer of vitamins, minerals and herbal supplements.
	https://www.hollandandbarrett.com/ https://www.gnc.co.uk/
	NBTY EU (Holland & Barrett brand) has nearly completed implementing phase 1 of their new eCommerce application on ATG 10.X/Endeca. Developed by Professional Access (PA), the application is now in UAT phase for soft launch (as of 8/7/13). NBTY

	has contracted us to take over for PA once they complete their soft launch / warranty phase. After that the project turned into a multi channel NBTY program: Holland & Barrett and GNC. Team: 23 people (project peak), 2 locations, 1 year.
Responsibilities	Development and customization, ATG/Endeca integration (app config, indexing, incremental updates mechanism), Endeca Preview (authoring), XM (site specific - segments, cartridges, microbrowser), SEO, Search, TypeAhead, Refinements, Multisite (H&B, GNC), GNC Blogs; bug fixing, code review, refactoring. Achievements: stable application for customer, excellent experience of working with legacy code and refactoring.
Used Technologies	Database: Oracle DB 11gR2. Tools: Eclipse, Weblogic, Oracle SQL Developer, Ant, TortoiseSVN, Jira, Confluence. Technologies: ATG 10.1.1, Endeca, Java EE 6, SQL, JSP, Web Services, Front End (JS, JQuery, CSS), Agile.
Project	EPAM KITS-DRWN (e-commerce)
Period	01/2013 - 07/2013
Role	Software Engineer
Description	B&Q (Kingfisher IT Services UK) is the largest home improvement and garden center retailer in the UK and Europe and the third largest in the world. https://www.diy.com/ https://www.trade-point.co.uk/ Darwin program for B&Q has been initiated to achieve business goals multi-channel strategy: - Multi channel shopping is becoming a way of life and customers

and other retailers are adopting rapidly;

- When purchasing a product or service, more than three-quarters of consumers use two or more channels to research and complete a transaction;
- Almost one-third of customers use three channels or more.

EPAM team prepares web and mobile implementation of Tradepoint and B&Q web store. Used development methodology: Agile (XP).

Team: 130 people (project peak), 4 locations, 1 year.

Responsibilities

Development and customization, multisite (TradePoint, DIY),
 SiteBuilder, ATG Search customization (facets, multi selection,
 predictive search, catalogs); knowledge transfer, consultancy (Kiev team, TCS); bug fixing, refactoring, code review.

Achievement: deep learning of methodologies and good practice in: XP, pair programming, TDD, Continuous Integration, Agile development process.

Used Technologies

Database: Oracle DB 11g.

Tools: Eclipse, Jenkins, Oracle SQL Developer, Jboss, Ruby/buildr, Fitness, WebSphere MQ Explorer, Git, Rally, Jira.
Technologies: ATG 10.0.3: Commerce, Search, CSC, CRS, User

profile, Data Anywhere Architecture, Content Administration,
Programming; Java EE 6; SiteBuilder CMS, SQL, JSP, Web services,
JUnit/Mockito, Groovy, Agile, XP: pair programming, TDD.

Project	EPAM KITS-MNT (e-commerce)
Period	08/2010 - 01/2013
Role	3rd Line / Software Maintenance Engineer, Software Engineer
Description	Castorama (Kingfisher IT services) is a French retailer of DIY and home improvement tools and supplies.

https://www.castorama.fr/

The objective of the project is customization of the castorama.fr website based on ATG 9.0/9.4 eCommerce platform.

Team: 8 people (project peak), 1 location, 3 years

Responsibilities

Maintenance, analyzing & estimating issues and defects, bug fixing, patch delivery (patches 21-28); development and customization, integration solutions (Google Merchant, Kelkoo, Experian, etc.), Click & Collect (double basket, multi store, product lifecycle solution, inventory, checkout customization), StockVis (stock visualization web services layer), FastLab (video how-to blogs), ATG Search customization (facets, multi selection); application migration (9.0 to 9.4); knowledge transfer (to support team); refactoring of the existing functionality.

Achievement: great customer support and communication experience.

Used Technologies

Database: Oracle DB 10g.

Tools: Jboss, Apache Web server, Ant, Eclipse, Oracle SQL Developer, SVN, Mantis, Epam PMC, My Oracle Support.

Technologies: ATG 9.0, ATG 9.4, ATG Search, Java EE 5/6, Spring, Hibernate, Web services, SQL, JSP, Front End (JS, JQuery, CSS).